Hello friends, you must have heard about
PI cover for owner driver in your car or bike insurance policy.
PI cover means
personal accident cover for owner and driver,
but many people do not know what it is and how much
amount can be claimed in case of an accident.
So in today's
video we will talk on this topic, so keep
watching the entire video to know more.
If you have taken an insurance policy for your car or bike, then
this personal
accident cover is included in it
because according to IRDA i.e. Insurance
Regulatory and Development Authority,
PI cover or personal accident cover
is mandatory, so it does not matter whether
you have taken a comprehensive insurance
policy or a third party insurance
policy. In both these types of policies, personal
accident cover for owner and driver
is included in which a claim of up to ₹1500000
is available. If you
want to understand the difference between comprehensive third party insurance policy,
then click on the like button above.
I have already made a video on this,
you can watch that video by clicking here.
So friends, we  Here we are talking
only about personal accident cover.
If a person meets with an
accident while driving his vehicle, be it a car or a bike,
and gets injured or
dies, then in that case the insurance
company provides cover up to ₹1500000. Earlier, this
insurance amount was one lakh rupees for a bike and up to
two lakh rupees for a car, the
premium of which was also very low, ranging from ₹50 and ₹100.
However,
since December 2018, IRDA has made personal accident cover for the owner
and driver ₹1500000 mandatory,
due to which the
motor insurance policy we are currently taking is getting a
bit expensive. Now let us talk about
what is meant by owner-driver in this policy. That is,
who will get the cover in the policy. Only the
person in whose name the vehicle
is registered and whose name is in the insurance policy will
get the cover in it, but one
condition is that the person must have a
valid driving license.
In short, it means that if the
person in whose name there is a car and insurance policy
and he meets with an accident
while driving, then he will be able to get a claim in it, but if
someone else was driving your car, then this
cover will not be available in it. Now let's talk about how much
insurance amount can be received in this, in
our personal accident cover, according to the
guidelines of IRDA, if the
insured person
dies
during an accident, then 100% means that a claim of up to ₹ 1500000 will be received
in it. If the insured person gets
permanent disability in any
way, like if he has lost
both his legs or
both his hands in an accident, then in this situation,
he will get 100%
amount of Rs 1500000 in permanent disability
and thirdly, if in an accident, one
organ gets damaged, for which one eye is damaged,
one of your hands is lost, then
in the same situation, you will get up to 50% insurance amount. So
friends, what is the method of making an anointed claim?  The
claim is that if due to
some reason an accident happens in this insurance
and you are taking it under the same insurance
policy, then the insured person gets his
insurance claim, whose
insurance one will get the claim, if the insured
person dies, then those who are
not the insured will also get the claim and
what is the method to claim it, then the best way to claim it is that
whenever you have the insurance policy of any company, then
talk to the customer care call center of that company and
whatever method they tell you from here, they
tell you the process that you submit this form, talk here, then
you can get it by following that process, so friends, this was
some information about the personal accident of this corner driver,
for more such information
click here and subscribe to our channel,
like the video and
share it with friends, click
here to watch videos related to investment and banking,
thank you
[Music]